Hi everyone.
皆様はじめまして。
If you saw the last record, welcome back. I'm Yue.
前回の記録を見てくれた皆様はお久しぶりです。ユエです。
Maki here
マキです。
It's golden week! (Multiple bank holidays)
ゴールデンウィークだ〜！
Why are you so excited?
テンション高くない？
What? It's one of the few times you can have a multiple day tour!
いや、だって何泊も可能な旅ができるんだよ。
Well true...
確かに。
Where are we heading?
どこに向かっているの？
We are heading to Nagasu port. There we'll catch the Ariake ferry to go to Nagasaki.
今は長洲港に向かっている。 そこから長崎に渡って明日のフェリーに向かうんだよ。
It's pretty windy.
風が強いね。
Yeah. I hope ferries are still running.
そうだよね。フェリーが出るか心配だね。。。
End of the uphill part?
登り区間がここまで？
Seems like it.
そうみたいね。
I think a great view is awaiting us.
ここからでも絶景がわかるね。
The sea is pretty.
海がきれい。
There is still time, but I want to stop somewhere nice to get a picture.
まだ遠いけどもうちょっといい場所があれば写真撮りたいな。。。
I'm sure there will be a spot to stop.
止まる場所はこの後あるでしょ。
I hope so.
そうだね。
The clouds are leaving.
雲も少なくなってきたね。
Yeah, there is even an angel ladder over there.
そうね、あそこにエンジェルラダーが見える。
It's hard to take.
写真だと難しいな。。。
It's the light between the pole and your mirror.
ミラーと柱の間に見える光。
I hope you can see it.
これ見えるかな。。。
If you follow the light from the bright spot on the water it could be a bit easier to see.
海の上の明るい場所から探すと見やすいかも？
Took a good picture, better than expected.
いやー。いい写真が撮れたね。
Yeah, it was a great spot.
だね。あそこはいい場所だったね。
Well time to slowly go to the ferry.
さてゆっくりフェリー乗り場に行こうか。
There is still time so let's enjoy the view.
まだ時間あるから、景色を楽しもう！
You're right. It could be the last time we see this scenery with this many clouds.
そうだね。こんな雲があるときにここを通るのは 今回が最後かもしれないしね。
Yeah, each time there are little changes so remember every scenery you see.
だね、ちょっとした変化を覚えて楽しむのもいいね。
Well, it's our privilege as inhabitants to see the scenery changing.
まー、その変化を楽しむのも、 付近に住んでいる私たちの特権だから。
Got to the ferry but it's delayed.
着いたけど、やはり欠航してるね。。。
There is still 2 hours before the next one.
次は2時間後か。。。
It's better to wait rather than use the highway.
今から高速乗ってもしょうがないしのんびり待とうか。
I'll have a nap then.
じゃ、ちょっと寝るわ。
Wake me up in an hour.
1時間後に起こして。
Okay.
オッケー。
Maki.
マキさ～ん。
You're awake?
起きてる？
Hmm.
ん～。。。
It's already an hour?
もう1時間？
Morning. Yup, we can board in 15 mins so we need to get ready. Well slept?
おはよう。そうだよ。 あと１５分で乗船できるみたい。よく寝れた？
Wasn't bad. Okay, I'll prepare myself.
そこそこ。準備しないと。
Here I come!
さて乗り込むぞ！
There is still some wind so beware.
まだ風があるから気をつけて。
Glad not all ferries are canceled.
フェリーが出てよかった。
Yeah, it's your turn to rest.
ユエが休む番。
You're right. I'll have a nap then.
そうだね、ちょっと仮眠するよ。
Boarding!
乗船！
Soon at the place we'll spend the night in.
もうすぐ今日の宿につくよ。
I've always wanted to go to that place.
前からここに来たかった。
Starting to see it but is it really ok?
見えてきたけど、本当にあそこでいいの？
Yeah, I can see it too.
私も見えてきた。
It's my second home so I'll show you around.
ちょこちょこ使うから案内するよ。
Thanks. I hope there are still some private rooms open.
ありがとう。まだ個室が空いているといいけど。
Feels like home!
ただいま～。
There's not much time so going to sleep asap.
そこまで時間がないから早く寝よう。
Good morning.
おはよう！
Today is another great day!
今日もすてきな朝が始まった！
Quarter past 5 is morning indeed but isn't it a bit early?
5時15分は朝だけども、早くない？
Want to get to the counter before it opens.
フェリーの受付開始時間より早く着きたい。
Ferry?
フェリー？
Again?
また？
Where are we going?
今度はどこ行くの？
Still a secret. I want to check another place as well so leaving early.
まだ秘密。でも途中、下見しながら早く着きたい。
Fine...
わかった。。。
The sun is slowly rising.
太陽が少しずつ出てきてる。
Indeed. The sun is slowly starting to rise up.
だね。ちょっとずつ明るくなってきたね。
You don't use the bypass?
バイパス使わないの？
There is still plenty of time. Normal roads should be empty. And that's a toll road...
まだ時間あるし。この時間帯だと 下道もすいているだろうし。バイパスは有料だからね。。。
Ah, I see well that's a fair point.
そうね、確かにそうだ。
And I want to see the path I used last year with my bike.
それに去年自転車で通った道をもう一回見てみたいなって。
That's a good idea!
それはいいね！
And want to check a secret place beforehand.
そのあと、とある場所の下見に行くよ。
You like your secrets, don't you?
秘密主義だね～。
We should arrive soon.
そろそろつくな？
The sun is finally out. But where are we?
太陽も出たけど。今どこ？
Wait a minute.
ちょっと待って。
On the right you can see the entrance to a certain parking.
今右に見える駐車場の入り口が下見したかった場所。
The parking of Mount Inasa Observation Deck. We'll come again once we're back.
ここは稲佐山山頂展望台の入り口。帰るとき絶景が見れるよ。
Oh, I'm excited!
おー、それは楽しみ！
Wait, wasn't Nagasaki famous for its night view?
ん？長崎って夜景が有名じゃなかったっけ？
Yup didn't expect you knew this.
そうだよ、よく知ってたね。
Well, it's in the top 3 after all...
日本三大夜景には入ってるからね。
Was too famous I see.
さすがに有名すぎたか。。。
But you have never seen it right?
あ～でも見たことないでしょ？
Nope I've never seen it.
うん、見たことない。
Then you cannot look up for this place until we go, okay?
じゃー、ここに戻るまで インターネットで調べるのは禁止！。。。オッケー？
Okay!
分かった。
Speaking of internet, I'd like to know where we are heading...
確認で思い出したが。。。どこに行こうとしてるの？
I'd like to check beforehand for places to visit...
行く前に観光地調べたい。。。
Hmm... I guess for the first place I can say it.
ん。。。さすがに最初の目的地は言ってもいいかな。。。
The first destination is...
最初の目的地はね。。。
Finally arrived!
着いたーーー。
Is this the boat we'll be using today?
今日のフェリーはこれ？
Indeed.
そうだよ！
I'll go to get tickets!
ちょっと手続きしてくる。
Yay. There were still some seats open.
よかったよかった。まだ空きがあった。
I cannot believe you really didn't book it...
本当に予約してなかったんだ。。。
Yah. It's sad if your perfect plan doesn't go as planned.
そうだよ、だってすべて計画してだめなら悲しいじゃん。
You have a point...
そうだけども。。。
What's fun traveling if there are no problems?
こういうのは適当のアドリブを楽しむのが一つだよ。
Yeah, yeah.
はいはい。
You said we were going to Fukue island right?
福江島に向かってるんだっけ？
Going to Fukue in the Gotō islands.
そう五島列島の福江島。
Looks like it's a pretty place.
なんか見どころ多そうだね。
I'm really excited. Wanted to go here for seven years.
本当に楽しみだ！7年前からずーっと行きたかった場所。
I bet it's a manga.
漫画で行きたくなったんだろうな。。。
Yeah, Barakamon
そうだよ。ばらかもんは本当に面白い！
Wait, this manga took place here?
えっ、あの漫画ってここだったの？！
You know this manga?!
えっ、マキさんも知ってるの？
Yeah, it was very fun!
うん。あれは面白かったよね。
Time to board!
さて、乗るぞ～！
I didn't expect the front to open like this.
まさか前がこうやって開くとは思わなった。
First time I see a boat open like that.
前が開くところは初めて見た。
Yeah. From what I saw, you go in from behind most of the time.
ね。普通はうしろから乗り込むよね。
Boarding!
乗船！
Don't slip.
気を付けてね。
Yeah, yeah.
はいはい。